# Jinhyuk Yoon

#### **POSTECH, Haptics and Virtual Reality Laboratory**

Rooms 011, Science Building 4, 77 Cheongam-Ro, Nam-Gu, Pohang, Gyeongbuk, Korea

jinhyukyoon@postech.ac.kr https://www.jinhyukyoon.com

I'm an interaction designer and engineer building interactive experience through tactile manipulation. I'm interested in a tactile interface which bridge between the world of digital and analog to bring a new paradigm of education. To broaden an insight for education, I've been participating in various projects such as start-up business, talk, performance, volunteer and art work. With deep interests in human-computer interaction, technology, and education, I have been trying to create meaningful experience.

# **Professional Experience**

## **POSTECH, Haptics and Virtual Reality Laboratory**

Feb 2019 - Present

Aug 2017 - Sep 2017

Research Intern

Developing a pneumatic haptic device to provide interactive tactile experiences.

Geekble Mar 2019 – Present

**Communications Manager** 

Designing contents for interactive education business which provide playful and empirical knowledge related to science and engineering.

Samsung Electronics, Digital Appliances Division, Core Component R&D Lab Jan 2019 – Feb 2019

Mechanical Design Intern

Analyzed mechanical property of spring and damper hinge mounted in oven door. Deployed the analysis result on interactive data platform to simplify design process.

**Sovoro** Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

Communications Manager

Conducted UI/UX research and design of the service, catalog design, and market research. Engaged in business activity related with public institution, educational institution, and people with hearing loss.

Korea Foundation for the Advancement of Science & Creativity

May 2016 – Jan 2018

Science Communicator

Gave talk, performed science street performance, and presented science play only for adult as a finalist of the FameLab Korea and a science communicator commissioned by minister of Ministry of Science & ICT.

minister of Ministry of Science & ICT.

Asan Medical Center, Biomedical Engineering Research Center

Research Intern

Designed concept prototype of Ankle Rehabilitation Assistant which analyzes ankle torque and provides rehabilitative movement.

# **Leadership Experience**

### **POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering**

Jan 2016 - Mar 2017

Student President

Directed student membership training, professor appreciation banquet, association program with KAIST and founded basketball and badminton club.

#### **POSTECH, Student Election Committee**

Sep 2016 - Nov 2016

Chairman

Organized the student election committee and run the election for central student president.

TEDxPOSTECH Nov 2014 – Nov 2015

Director

Organized TEDx event under the theme 'question' with 6 speakers. Regular application was fully booked in 50 seconds after opening. Conducted team building, speaker and sponsor contact, stage planning and host at the event.

# **Education**

### **Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering**

2014 - Present

Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH)

Minor in Industrial Management Engineering. Expect to graduate with *Magna Cum Laude* 

## **Awards and Honors**

<b>Commission Letter</b> Minister of Ministry of Science & ICT commissioned me as a science communicator	2016
<b>Finalist</b> Nationwide Top 11 of the 3 <sup>rd</sup> FameLab Korea	2016
Runners Up Artience Creation Challenge 30x30 hosted by British Council	2017
Honorable Mention 3 Minutes Science Speech Contest hosted by POSTECH	2015
Student of the Year POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering	2015, 2016
<b>The 4<sup>th</sup> Prize</b> The 2 <sup>nd</sup> POSTECH Hackathon	2016

### **National Academic Excellence Scholarship**

2016 - Present

## **KT&G Foundation Scholarship**

POSTECH

Jigok Scholarship 2014 – 2016

2016

POSTECH

# **Skills and Tools**

## **Programming Language**

C, C++, JAVA, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MATLAB

## **Graphic Design**

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, After Effects, InDesign

## **3D Design & Analysis**

Solidworks, NX

# **Selected Talks**

2018
2016
2016
2018
2017
2016
2017
2017
2017